Yuvraj Upadhyay

406,Abhilasha Complex,
Satelite, Ahmedabad
Gujarat-380051
7600104483
upadhyayyuvi@gmail.com

ABOUT

As a Senior Backend Developer with over **Five years of experience** in web development using Node.js, I have gained valuable expertise in creating web solutions tailored to meet client requirements. My expertise includes database design, code review, team management, and server management.

EXPERIENCE

Bytes Technolab, Ahmedabad — Sr. Software Engineer

Jul 2023 - PRESENT

- Contributing to backend development, database design, and API construction.
- I also gained valuable leadership and team management skills by successfully leading and managing a team of developers in a dynamic and challenging environment.

Mind Inventory, Ahmedabad — *Sr. Software Engineer*

Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

- Work on Game Backend name as Dice prisoner.
- Work on Blackjack Game with Socket and event base
- Work on Dot Box Game

Yudiz Solutions Ltd, Ahmedabad — Backend Developer

lan 2022 - Dec 2022

- Worked on multiple game backend. Also worked as a full stack developer in BFK Warzone.
- Configure Projects from scratch.
- Database design.
- Collaborate with the UI/UX & QA team.
- Deploy, Test, and Server Management.
- Discuss problem solutions and code reviews.
- Communicate with clients.

SKILLS

Node.JS

NestJs

GraphQL

MongoDB

JavaScript

SQL

AWS EC2

Docker

React JS

HTML

CSS

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Gujarati

Yudiz Solutions Ltd, Ahmedabad — Blockchain Developer

Jan 2019 - Dec 2021

- Worked on Blockchain Based Projects's backend like Web Application, NFT Marketplace, etc. and other whitelable Projects.
- Review client requirements and sprints.
- Discuss & Design Database, UI/UX, Wireframes.
- Provide APIs and integrate with the frontend.
- Deploy, Test, and Server Management.
- Mentor and guide new interns.

EDUCATION

Nirma University, Ahmedabad — MCA

2016 - 2019

Gujarat University, Ahmedabad — BCA

2013 - 2016

PROJECTS

Snapjob - Job portal

Blackjack - Card Game

Dot Box — Casual Game

Dice Prisoner — Puzzle Game backend

BFK Warzone — Action Game backend

BFK Warzone Marketplace— Platform for buy and sell Fortis (NFT) and use in game

High Card ETH Game — Card Game

Whitelabel NFT — *Platform for buying and selling NFTs.*

Bones Club NFT — *Platform for buy NFT*

Web Casino — *Slot Game*

Prediction Website — Betting on ETH, BTC price

MacQueen — P2P platform for travelers

Forest Conservation — Related to Environment , Investors can invest on forest

Voting System — *Dapp For Secure voting*